ANDY NGUYEN

904-424-3332 anguyen1119@gmail.com andycodes.io github.com/andydnguyen

Self-driven and highly motivated software developer looking for the opportunity to expand my technical skill set. I have 5 years of progressive experience as a software developer working mostly with an application called AXAEM. In my free time, I like to work on extracurricular projects and collaborate with other developers on projects where I can improve my knowledge for continuous personal growth.

Technical Skill

Javascript (ECMAScript2019)

CSS

React (w/ Redux)

JQuery

Express

Git

SQL

✓ HTML5

EXPERIENCE

APPX Software Inc – Jacksonville, FL

Software Developer

March 2017 - Present

- Oversee the development of AXAEM, an application currently utilized by 5 states and one university archive
- Act as the first point of contact for all issues and features related to AXAEM
- Collaborate and act as a team lead on all stages of the systems development lifecycle, from gathering requirements to production releases utilizing an Agile project management approach
- Manage and oversee the project management tool Trello, assigning responsibilities, establishing priorities and manage deliverables
- Respond to client requests regarding new features, consult with clients regarding project progress, oversees all change requests
- Debug and troubleshoot applications for clients, resolving technical issues quickly and accurately to better facilitate end user experience
- Perform testing on software to uncover bugs and troubleshoot issues before application launches
- Back up and upgrade client's test and production server to the latest release
- Travel to out of state conferences to promote AXAEM to all attendees and meet with existing clients to promote positive account
- Train, supervise, and coach interns on a daily basis, discussing issues on how to best provide resolutions and apply industry best practices
- Create and alter work instructions, documenting technical workflows and knowledge to better streamline processes for end users as well as education of employees
- Utilized: APPX, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, Apache Solr

APPX Software Inc – Jacksonville, FL

May 2015 - March 2017

Software Developer Intern

- Collaborated with the team in developing, testing, and debugging software and functions
- Developed code fixes and enhancements for inclusion in future code releases and patches
- Met with project team lead on a weekly basis to provide detailed project report and milestone updates
- Utilized: APPX, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL

Projects

Now That's Delicious! - http://nowthatsdelicious.andycodes.io/

September 2019 - Present

- Node.js application, using MVC design pattern, which users can search, geolocate, review and curate their favorite restaurants
- The app itself makes full use of ECMAScript2019 JavaScript with extensive templating and mixins with PUG
- It is designed to hit upon many of today's application needs such as user authentication, database storage, Ajax REST API, file upload, image resizing, password reset flow, pagination, sending email, and many more
- Utilized: JavaScript (ES2019), Node.js, MongoDB, Google Map API, PUG, Express, Passport

Catch of the Day! – https://catchoftheday.andycodes.io/

October 2019

- This was designed principally as a CRUD app to help teach the basics of React. Users can add, remove, and update fish in the inventory.
- The app itself makes full use of ECMAScript2019 JavaScript with extensive templating with JSX
- Extensive use of React components (including stateless functional components)
- Utilized: JavaScript (ECMAScript2019), React 16.3, Async + Await, React Router 4, Firebase, NPM, HTML5 localStorage, PropType Package

Education

Bachelor of Science in Computer and Information Science, Computer Science concentration

University of North Florida, Graduated December 2016